Guide to the Willis Knapp Jones Latin American Theatre Programs
University of Houston Libraries
Willis Knapp Jones Latin American Theatre Programs
1939-1961
2007-017
Jones, Willis Knapp, 1895-1982
1.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contains theatre programs from 1939-1961.
Biographical Information:
Willis Knapp Jones was born on November 26, 1895 in Beacon, New York, the son of Plato Tydvil and Louise (Knapp) Jones. He received his AB from Hamilton College in 1917. He received his MA from Pennsylvania State University in 1922. In 1927 he received his Ph.D. from the University of Chicago. He taught at Penn State, instructor in Spanish (1920-23), University of Miami, Oxford, Ohio, associate professor (1923-28), professor of Romance languages (1928-63). During his school year and life span he travelled and taught in Santiago, Chile (1917-1919), in Montevideo, Uruguay (1919-1920), American University of Shrivenham, England (1945) and at the University of Guayaquil, Ecuador, a Lecturer on Latin American drama and culture (1946-1947). Upon his retirement in 1963 he sold his library of Latin American theatrical works to the University of Houston. He died in March 1982, in Oxford, Ohio.
Dr. Jones was a true pioneer in the study of Latin American literature bringing Spanish texts and translation to American readers by the way of his research and publications of books, journals and newspapers.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Theater programs
Topical Term:
Performing arts -- Latin America; Theater
Acquisition Information:
Dr. Willis Knapp Jones
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains theatre programs from 1939-1961.
Detailed List of Contents
- (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Teatro Estudiantil de La Universitario, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Teatro Estudiantil de La Unam, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - Temporada de Primavera del Teatro del Aire, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Temporada de Primavera del Teatro del Aire, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Conjunto Teatral Nuevos Horizontes, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Conjunto Teatral Nuevos Horizontes, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Conjunto Teatral Nuevos Horizontes, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 7)
  - Conjunto Teatral Nuevos Horizontes, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 8)
  - Conjunto Teatral Nuevos Horizontes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 9)
  - Conjunto Teatral Nuevos Horizontes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 10)
  - Conjunto Teatral Nuevos Horizontes, undated (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 11)
  - Teatro Experimental, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 12)
  - Teatro Experimental, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 13)
  - Teatro Experimental, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 14)
  - Teatro Experimental, undated (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 15)
  - Teatro Experimental, undated (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 16)
  - Escuela Municipal de Arte Escenico, October 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 17)
  - Escuela Municipal de Arte Escenico, October 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1, Item 18)
- (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Convivencia, no.42, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 7)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 8)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 9)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 10)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 11)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 12)
  - Teatro De Ensayo De La Universidad Catolica, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 13)
- (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Primer Salon Municipal de Arte, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Wolf, Egon. "Parejas De Trapo." Instituto Del Teatro, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Lorca, Federico G. "La Casa De Bernarda Alba." Instituto Del Teatro, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - Marques, Rene. "Palm Sunday." Teatro Tapia, October 26-28, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Cuadra, Fernando. "El Mandamas." Teatro Bancario, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - Pruvonena, no.26, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - Comedia Nacional, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 7)
- (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Pan American Theatre, July-August 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - Gajardo, Enrique V. "Alberto Blest Gana", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - "Moliere:El Enfermo Imaginario", undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 3)